Welcome back. So, here's my solution for the validation pass.
欢迎回来下面说说我的验证流程实现方法
So, here, our model has been defined,
在这里定义模型
our loss, and our optimizer, and all this stuff.
损失 优化器等等
I've set to 30 epochs so we can see like how this trains or how the training loss drops,
我将周期设成了 30   可以更清晰地看到训练效果
and how the validation loss changes over time.
损失如何下降 验证损失如何变化 等等
The way this works is that after each pass,
原理是 每个周期之后
after each epoch, after each pass through the training set,
即 每次经过训练集之后
then we're going to do a validation pass.
我们将执行训练流程
That's what this else here means.
这就是这个 else 的作用
So, basically, four of this stuff and then
这是 for 循环
else basically says after this four loop completes,
for 循环之后
then run this code.
运行此代码
That's what this else here means.
这就是 else 的含义
As seen before, we want to turn off our gradients so with torch.no_grad,
我们要关闭梯度 所以使用 with torch.no_grad
and then we're going to get our images and labels from a test set,
然后从测试集获取图像和标签
pass it into the images into our model to get our log probabilities, calculate our loss.
将图像传入模型 获取对数概率 计算损失
So, here, I am going to just be updating our test_loss.
在这里更新 test_loss
So, test_loss is just an integer that's going to count
test_loss 是一个整数
up our loss on our test set as we're training,
当我们在训练时 或者说 在执行验证流程时
as we're doing more of these validation passes.
test_loss 会计数
So, this way, we can actually track
这样就能够跟踪
the test loss over all the epochs that we're training.
所有训练周期的测试损失
So, from the law of probabilities,
使用 torch.exp
I can get our actual probability distributions using torch.exponential.
从对数概率中获得实际概率分布
Again, topk1 gives us our predicted classes and we can measure,
运行 topk(1, dim=1) 其中前面的 1表示预测类别
we can calculate the equalities.
我们可以衡量相等性
So, here, we can get our probabilities from our log probabilities using torch.exp,
我们在这里使用 torch.exp 从对数概率中获取概率
taking the exponential of a log gives you back into the probabilities.
用对数计算指数可以得出概率
From that, we do ps.topk, so one,
然后运行 ps.topk(1, dim=1)
and this gives us the top_class or predicted class from the network.
前面的 1 表示概率最高的类别或预测类别
Then, using checking for equality,
然后使用 ==
we can see where our predicted classes match with the true classes from labels.
检测预测类别与标签的真实类别是否匹配
Again, measure our calculator accuracy.
使用 torch.mean 计算准确率
So, using torch.mean and changing equals into a FloatTensor.
并将 equals 变成浮点数张量
So, I'm going to run this and then let it run for a while,
运行此单元格
and then we can see what the actual training
看看在训练此网络时
and validation losses look like as we were training this network.
实际训练损失和验证损失是多少
Now, the network is trained, we can see how
网络训练过后
the validation loss and the training loss actually
可以看出当我们继续用更多数据训练网络时
changed over time like as we continue training on more and more data.
验证损失和训练损失是如何逐渐改变的
So, we see is the training loss drops but
训练损失降低了
the validation loss actually starts going up over time.
但是验证损失开始上升了
There's actually a clear sign of overfitting
很明显地表现出过拟合了
so our network is getting better and better and better on the training data,
网络在训练数据上的效果越来越好
but it's actually starting to get worse on the validation data.
但是在验证数据上的效果开始变差
This is because as it's learning the training data,
这是因为它在学习训练数据中的细节
it's failing to generalize the data outside of that.
但无法泛化到训练数据之外的数据上
Okay. So, this is what the phenomenon of overfitting looks like.
Ok这就是过拟合现象
The way that we combine it,
要避免或者防止过拟合
the way that we try to avoid this and prevent it is by
我们将使用正则化
using regularization and specifically, dropout.
例如丢弃
So, deep behind dropout is that we randomly drop input units between our layers.
丢弃是指在层级之间随机丢弃输入单元
What this does is it forces the network to share information between the weights,
这样可以强制网络在权重之间共享信息
and so this increases this ability to generalize to new data.
并提高网络泛化到新数据上的能力
PyTorch adding dropout is pretty straightforward.
在 PyTorch 中添加丢弃很简单
We just use this nn.Dropout module.
直接使用 nn.Dropout 模块
So, we can basically create our classifier like we had before
像之前一样创建分类器
using the linear transformations to do our hidden layers,
在隐藏层使用线性转换
and then we just add self.dropout,
然后设置为 self.dropout = nn.Dropout
nn.Dropout, and then you give it some drop probability.
并设定丢弃概率
In this case, this is 20 percent,
我们设为 20%
so this is the probability that you'll drop a unit.
表示丢弃某个单元的概率
In the forward method, it's pretty similar.
forward 方法很相似
So, we just pass in x,
传入 x
which is our input tensor,
x 是输入张量
we're going to make sure it's flattened,
我们需要先扁平化 x
and then we pass this tensor through each of
然后将此张量传入每个全连接层
our fully connected layers into an activation,
传入 ReLu 激活函数
relu activation and then through dropout.
再传入 dropout
Our last layer is the output layer so we're not going to use dropout here.
最后一层是输出层 因此不使用丢弃
There's one more thing to note about this.
还有一点要注意
So, when we're actually doing inference,
在进行推理时
if we're trying to make predictions with our network,
就是 在使用网络做出预测时
we want to have all of our units available, right?
我们需要使用所有单元
So, in this case,
因此 在进行验证时、
we want to turn off dropout when we're doing validation,
在网络尝试做出预测时
testing, when we're trying to make predictions.
我们都必须关闭丢弃
So, to do that, we do model.eval.
运行 model.eval
So, model.eval will turn off dropout and this will allow us to get the most power,
model.eval 将关闭丢弃
the highest performance out of our network when we're doing inference.
才能在进行推理时充分利用网络的强大功能
Then, to go back in the train mode, use model.train.
要回到训练模式 则使用 model.train
So, then, the validation pass looks like this now.
现在验证流程看起来是这样的
So, first, we're going to turn off our gradients.
首先使用 with torch.no_grad 关闭梯度
So, with torch.no_grad, and then we set our model to evaluation mode,
然后将模型设为验证模式
and then we do our validation pass through the test data.
对测试数据执行验证流程
Then, after all this,
结束后
we want to make sure the model is set back to train mode so we do model.train.
我们可以用 model.train 将模型设回训练模式
Okay. So, now, I'm going to leave it up to you to create your new model.
Ok.下面你的任务是创建新的模型
Try adding dropout to it and then try training your model with dropout.
向模型中添加丢弃并训练模型
Then, again, checkout the training progress of validation using dropout. Cheers.
然后使用丢弃通过验证流程检查训练进度加油！